<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/blog</id>
    <title>SAP Architecture Center Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/blog"/>
    <subtitle>SAP Architecture Center Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/img/logo.svg</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the Launch of SAP Architecture Center]]></title>
        <id>https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/blog/2025/05/15/announcing-the-launch-of-sap-architecture-center</id>
        <link href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/blog/2025/05/15/announcing-the-launch-of-sap-architecture-center"/>
        <updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The SAP Architecture Center centralizes all resources in one place, enabling organizations to maximize cloud capabilities while ensuring that their solutions are secure, resilient, and optimized to their specific requirements.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="launching-the-sap-architecture-center">Launching the SAP Architecture Center!<a href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/blog/2025/05/15/announcing-the-launch-of-sap-architecture-center#launching-the-sap-architecture-center" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Launching the SAP Architecture Center!" title="Direct link to Launching the SAP Architecture Center!">​</a></h2>
<p>I'm pleased to announce that my team at the Office of the CTO, SAP, has officially launched the <a href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAP Architecture Center on the SAP Learning Center</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Why did we create it?</strong> In the past, we've relied on various tools, ranging from PowerPoint presentations to static websites, for documenting and sharing technical architectures. These methods, however, lacked collaborative authoring capabilities, robust version control, and ease of iterative refinement. To address these limitations, we've transitioned to a modern, collaborative solution using GitHub, a widely recognized platform among developers and architects.</p>
<p><strong>What is the SAP Architecture Center?</strong> The SAP Architecture Center is a GitHub-based repository designed to enhance how we build, publish, and govern Reference Solution Architectures. Each architecture is managed through Markdown files on <a href="https://github.com/SAP/architecture-center" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub</a>, supporting transparent collaboration, robust version control, and structured governance. Solution diagrams utilize draw.io, an open-source tool, and integrate seamlessly into our official <a href="https://sap.github.io/btp-solution-diagrams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solution Diagrams repository</a>, managed by Fabian Lehmann.</p>
<p><strong>How does it work?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Efficient collaboration across teams.</li>
<li>Robust version control for architectures.</li>
<li>Collective enhancement and evolution of architectures.</li>
<li>Structured governance with clear review and approval workflows.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What's next?</strong> SAPPHIRE 2025 was our initial launch milestone, marking the start of this journey. Moving forward, we have several strategic enhancements planned:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Automated Architecture Validator</strong> with Joule Interface: Solution diagrams will include embedded service metadata, enabling AI-powered automated validation and testing through Joule.</li>
<li><strong>Integration with Learning Journeys</strong>: Enhanced integration with SAP Learning Center Learning Journeys for certifications and accreditations, along with closer alignment with SAP Discovery Center’s service catalog and missions.</li>
<li><strong>Expanded Architectures</strong>: New architectures in data and agentic AI—including open-source collaborations such as A2A interoperability—and additional architectures addressing non-functional requirements like HA/DR, security, and observability.</li>
</ol>
<p>Special acknowledgment to Philipp Herzig and Andre Bechtold for sponsorship, the core team: James Rapp, Pierre-Olivier Basseville, Navya Khurana, Fabian Lehmann, Michael Still, Marina Noble, Julian, Johanna, Vedant, Gabriel, Robin, Max, Jonas, Praveen, and all contributors.</p>
<p>Join us in shaping the future of SAP architecture."</p>
<p><a href="https://architecture.learning.sap.com/@preview/cernus76-update-anirbans-blog-post/community/contribution">Start contributing</a> today.</p>
<p>Anirban
Office of the CTO</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Anirban Majumdar</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/anirban-sap</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>